<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 12:00:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Get your free ecommerce store evaluation</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19646</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Running an ecommerce business is a lot of work, we get it. It’s easy to lose perspective when you’re juggling so many priorities: is your site design drawing customers or chasing them away? Are you giving customers a memorable shopping experience that will keep them coming back or losing them before they hit checkout? The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/">Get your free ecommerce store evaluation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Running an ecommerce business is a lot of work, we get it.</p>
<p>It’s easy to lose perspective when you’re juggling so many priorities: is your site design drawing customers or chasing them away? Are you giving customers a memorable shopping experience that will keep them coming back or losing them before they hit checkout?</p>
<p>The beginning of the year is a great time to step back and take a look at your site, before summer sales and the back-to-school season descend upon us (they’ll be here before you know it!). To help give you perspective, we’ve launched an Ecommerce Evaluation of the Month project.<span id="more-19646"></span></p>
<p>Each month, one lucky business owner will get a thorough site evaluation by our in-house ecommerce experts, who will identify what’s working well and what could be tweaked to attract more customers and build a healthy long-term online business. The store will be featured on our blog.</p>
<p>Here are just a few of the things our evaluation will address:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 30px;font-style: italic">
<li>Traffic</li>
<li>Conversions</li>
<li>User experience</li>
<li>Images</li>
<li>Customer loyalty</li>
</ul>
<p>We’ll publish the evaluations on our blog so everyone in our community can learn from one another and benefit from seeing best practices in action.</p>
<p>Ready to get personalized advice for your ecommerce store and learn from other stores?<br />
Email us at <a href="mailto:ecommerce-evaluation@prestashop.com">ecommerce-evaluation@prestashop.com</a> to enter for a chance to get your free online store evaluation.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/">Get your free ecommerce store evaluation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A guided visit of PrestaShop’s new Paris headquarters</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/guided-visit-prestashops-new-paris-headquarters/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/guided-visit-prestashops-new-paris-headquarters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 12:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In the eight years since PrestaShop was founded in 2007, 230,000 stores have been created and 800,000 members welcomed into our worldwide ecommerce community. The PrestaShop story has been marked by several important milestones, and March 31, 2015 is no doubt one of the most exciting: on that brisk morning, 115 PrestaShop Paris employees discovered [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/guided-visit-prestashops-new-paris-headquarters/">A guided visit of PrestaShop’s new Paris headquarters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the eight years since PrestaShop was founded in 2007, 230,000 stores have been created and 800,000 members welcomed into our worldwide ecommerce community. The PrestaShop story has been marked by several important milestones, and March 31, 2015 is no doubt one of the most exciting: on that brisk morning, 115 PrestaShop Paris employees discovered their brand new office, a fresh, convivial space that embodies the PrestaShop team spirit.</p>
<p>Come on and explore #PrestaShopHQ with us!</p>
<p>The building was impossible to miss: an enormous banner waved a welcome to teams on opening day. (We’re still wondering how they got it up there…)<br />
<span id="more-19888"></span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19891" alt="Banner" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Banner-1024x276.jpg" /></p>
<p>Once over the threshold, PrestaShop’s unique working philosophy is evident.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19901" alt="Work like a Captain Play like a Pirate" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/work-like.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>The airy, open plan offices are set up to encourage communication between teams.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19895" alt="offices" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/IMG_2902.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>The break room is a central meeting point for PrestaShop teams. The walls are colorfully adorned with tags and artwork created specially for PrestaShop by Parisian street artists. © tacks and nix</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19894" alt="Kitchen" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/cafêt.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>Who do we have here? We’d like to introduce you to Preston, the latest PrestaShop recruit! He’s now an irreplacable member of the family.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19897" alt="Puffin code" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Puffin-code.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>He loves to change things up and can be found throughout the office sporting many different outfits.</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-4 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19899" alt="Yoda Puffin" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/puffin-yoda.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-4 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19900" alt="Puffins" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/puffins.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-4 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19898" alt="puffin hipster" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/puffin-hip.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></div>
</div>
<p>Attention, you are entering an intensive fun zone! This is where teams take a break for a game of foosball or a round of MarioKart before getting back to work. ©kuhuru</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19893" alt="Bungalow" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/bungalow.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>For those who prefer a bit of calm to recharge, there’s a room dedicated to afternoon cat naps.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19892" alt="Break" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/break.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>Speaking of cats…meet Puff Daddy, our newest resident! He’ll be living and working alongside the PrestaShop teams too.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19896" alt="Puff Daddy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Puff-Daddy.jpg" width="1026" height="684" /></p>
<p>This is just a glimpse of how we work at PrestaShop. For a better idea of what it’s like to work for PrestaShop, head on over to Pinterest and take a look at our <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/prestashop/working-at-prestashop/" target="_blank">Working at PrestaShop board</a> or follow us on Instagram <a href="https://instagram.com/prestacrew/" target="_blank">@prestacrew</a>.</p>
<p>Want to join our team? Check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/careers" target="_blank">Careers page</a> and send us your application today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/guided-visit-prestashops-new-paris-headquarters/">A guided visit of PrestaShop’s new Paris headquarters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/guided-visit-prestashops-new-paris-headquarters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A mom and an entrepreneur? Gretel Home’s mommypreneur is living proof it’s possible</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/mom-entrepreneur-gretel-homes-mommypreneur-living-proof-possible/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/mom-entrepreneur-gretel-homes-mommypreneur-living-proof-possible/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 13:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19866</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>An inconvenient truth for most women like myself is that we often have to sacrifice time in order to start our family &#8211;time that usually falls smack-dab in the middle of our careers. Do we choose to spend our time doing what we love or be there to experience our children’s “firsts”? The hardest part [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/mom-entrepreneur-gretel-homes-mommypreneur-living-proof-possible/">A mom and an entrepreneur? Gretel Home’s mommypreneur is living proof it’s possible</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An inconvenient truth for most women like myself is that we often have to sacrifice time in order to start our family &#8211;time that usually falls smack-dab in the middle of our careers. Do we choose to spend our time doing what we love or be there to experience our children’s “firsts”? The hardest part about this choice is that there is no <strong style="font-style: italic">easy</strong> answer&#8211;and more importantly, no <strong style="font-style: italic">right</strong> answer.</p>
<p>Mommypreneur and <a href="http://gretelhome.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Merchant Abby Kellett</a> decided she wanted to take part in her daughters Beatrice and Josephine’s lives, even if it meant leaving her career. This choice allowed Abby to spend time with both her daughters and watch them grow. But Abby soon realized that the enjoyment she got from being a mom couldn’t replace her passion for interior design. So she searched for opportunities that would allow her to be a mother and work in interior design at the same time. The perfect compromise was to launch <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/" target="_blank">Gretel Home</a>, an online interior design store, with PrestaShop. Read on to hear all about Abby’s mommypreneur story.<br />
<span id="more-19866"></span><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19867" alt="home" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/home.png" width="1004" height="757" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #ebba9f">Becoming an online entrepreneur</h2>
<p>Opening an online store allowed Abby to both be a mommy and pursue her professional passion. Abby shares, “I was always passionate about design, I studied interior design then worked as a stylist at Elle Decoration in London.” She draws on her interior design background to hand-pick home goods for her online shop. Running an online business gives her the flexibility to work from anywhere, anytime.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ebba9f">From launch to ecommerce success</h2>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-19868" alt="rabbit" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/rabbit.png" width="248" height="205" /></p>
<p>Abby, a non-technical entrepreneur, hired a freelancer to set up <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/" target="_blank">Gretel Home</a>. PrestaShop came highly recommended because of its flexibility and low-cost maintenance. Even as Abby continues to grow her business, her shop can be scaled to accommodate more customers and products. Another perk: Abby was able to customize her shop’s look to make it feel warm and homey. She decorated with a touch of floral and peach, then crafted welcoming text throughout her website.</p>
<p>Nine months after Abby decided to go it on her own, she launched her PrestaShop store. She hand picks each piece of houseware sold on Gretel Home is for its crafty, yet modern look. Whether it’s a <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/roros-tweed/1025-lynild-blanket-in-pink-and-green.html" target="_blank">blanket from a historic hill-top mill</a> in Norway or <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/oli-carol/1109-red-mushroom-chewable-toy.html" target="_blank">whimsical baby chew toys</a> made in Morocco, they each add a little bit of character to their eventual homes.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-19869" alt="window" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/window.png" width="257" height="212" /></p>
<p>For these pieces to find a home, Abby’s online store needs website visits. To drive traffic, Abby attended art festivals; including the Miami Art Basel, where she passed out business cards with links to <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/" target="_blank">Gretel Home</a>. For an extra boost of visibility, she reached out to major design magazines for feature opportunities. Gretel Home’s housewares have been featured in <a href="http://tmagazine.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/04/02/good-enough-to-eat-pieces-of-porcelain/" target="_blank">T Magazine by Times Magazine</a>, <a href="http://www.realsimple.com/work-life/life-strategies/problem-solving-products-10" target="_blank">Real Simple Magazine</a>, <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/content/12-Press" target="_blank">Martha Stewart Living</a> and <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/content/12-Press" target="_blank">Elle Decor</a>, <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/content/12-Press" target="_blank">among others</a>. “Once a piece is featured; the product sells out on Gretel Home. It’s obvious that people love these designs; they just need to be able to find my shop,” says Abby, from Gretel Home.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ebba9f">Ecommerce versus Brick and Mortar</h2>
<p>A year after launching her online business, Abby considered opening a physical retail store. It would have been a great opportunity to grow Gretel Home’s presence in Miami. But although it was tempting, Abby remembered the reason she had initially started selling online: having the freedom to spend time with her children.</p>
<p>Unlike her online store, a brick and mortar shop would have required her to be on site during opening hours. It would also require a large financial commitment &#8212; leasing a storefront and keeping it staffed.</p>
<p>Having a unique online presence has benefits of its own. Gretel Home welcomes customers from all over the world to shop hand-selected designs. Abby jokes, “My knowledge of US geography has vastly improved.” Since launching her shop, Gretel Home goods have arrived in homes in major cities like New York City and Tokyo to small towns in North Dakota.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ebba9f">From a passion for interior design to a successful business</h2>
<p>It’s now been five years since Gretel Home first launched. Abby turned her passion for beautiful interiors into a full-fledged successful business. Abby currently employs a team of 5 stylists and graphic designers that assist her in freelance styling jobs, styling Gretel Home sponsored events and day-to-day ecommerce operations.</p>
<h2 style="color: #ebba9f">Having a career and a family too!</h2>
<p>Abby is more than a PrestaShop merchant&#8211;she’s an inspiration to all mommies considering starting their online store. She’s living proof that being both a mom and an entrepreneur is possible. By having the courage to make her children a priority, she gave herself the opportunity to transform her passion into a successful online store.</p>
<p>Now it’s your turn. Are you a mommy inspired to launch your own online store? Get started selling online with <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/">PrestaShop Cloud</a>. We’re making it simple to start by providing a free shopping cart software hosted at no cost, with no monthly fee or commissions on your sales.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/mom-entrepreneur-gretel-homes-mommypreneur-living-proof-possible/">A mom and an entrepreneur? Gretel Home’s mommypreneur is living proof it’s possible</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/mom-entrepreneur-gretel-homes-mommypreneur-living-proof-possible/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Le Slip Français: From Friendly Bet to International Success</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/le-slip-francais-friendly-bet-international-success/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/le-slip-francais-friendly-bet-international-success/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 13:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sabrina Maréchal]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19837</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the most unique French e-commerce sites on the marketplace was launched in September 2011 after a friendly bet. Is it possible, the friends wondered, to launch a successful venture in any field whatsoever, with nothing but a nice story and beautiful French-made products? &#8220;Not with just anything,&#8221; came the challenge. &#8220;For example, it&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/le-slip-francais-friendly-bet-international-success/">Le Slip Français: From Friendly Bet to International Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most unique French e-commerce sites on the marketplace was launched in September 2011 after a friendly bet. Is it possible, the friends wondered, to launch a successful venture in any field whatsoever, with nothing but a nice story and beautiful French-made products? &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">Not with just anything,</span>&#8221; came the challenge. &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">For example, it&#8217;s impossible with men&#8217;s briefs!</span>&#8221; Guillaume Gibault, a 26-year-old HEC graduate, replied: &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">Impossible with men&#8217;s briefs? Not if they&#8217;re French!</span>&#8221;</p>
<p>Fast forward to the present. <strong>Guillaume currently employs 15 people at</strong> <a href="http://www.leslipfrancais.fr/en" target="_blank">Leslipfrancais.fr</a> and <strong>earned €1.5 million in revenue in 2014</strong>.</p>
<p>I had a chance to speak with Clément Coignac, Web Manager at Le Slip Français, who told me this exciting story about men&#8217;s briefs.<br />
<span id="more-19837"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #337f97;">Ambitious First Steps</h2>
<p>After his bet, Guillaume had 600 pairs of briefs made in a small factory in Dordogne. He brought them back to Paris in the trunk of his car. To sell them, he created his first e-commerce site by himself. He used the PrestaShop platform because &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">it&#8217;s simple, flexible, let me launch alone at first, and it was quick to set up.</span>&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>The first order came the day the site launched.</strong> These briefs were on a path to success!</p>
<h2 style="color: #337f97;">The Briefs Take Off</h2>
<p>The spotlight started to shine on Le Slip Français during the 2012 Presidential Campaign. At first it was difficult to see the connection. But it was there!</p>
<p>The &#8220;Made in France&#8221; issue was one of the central themes of the campaign. By creatively altering the campaign posters of several candidates in the election, Guillaume’s underwear stole the spotlight from politicians. The media immediately picked up on this unusual marketing campaign, and Le Slip Français was soon featured on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/leslipfrancais/videos" target="_blank">all of the major national media outlets, from the &#8220;20 heures&#8221; evening news program on TF1 to Le Figaro and Canal +</a>.</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-3 col-xs-12 text-center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19841" alt="Nicolas Sarkozy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/1927904_sarkozy.jpg" width="240" height="318" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 col-xs-12 text-center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19839" alt="François Hollande" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/1927904_hollande.jpg" width="240" height="403" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 col-xs-12 text-center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19852" alt="François Bayrou" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/1927904_bayrou.jpg" width="239" height="334" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-3 col-xs-12 text-center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19840" alt="Mélenchon" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/1927904_melenchon.jpg" width="294" height="196" /></div>
</div>
<h2 style="color: #337f97;">A Huge Boost in Sales and an Expanded Product Line</h2>
<p>By Christmas, Le Slip Français had become a victim of its own success. &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">On December 10, our inventory was practically down to zero. Our brand works very well for gifts: Christmas, Father&#8217;s Day, and Valentine&#8217;s Day all have a very big impact on our sales. <strong>We make a quarter of our sales in November and December alone.</strong></span>&#8221;</p>
<p>Guillaume gradually decided to expand his product line while staying with the typically French basics that brought him his success: briefs, boxers, socks, and T-shirts, as well as slippers, espadrilles, and pétanque balls. In 2013, he launched a swimsuit collection that sold out in just one week.</p>
<p>Today, the company works with about 15 suppliers, including the original factory. The majority of production is now in Lille, &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">in a factory that&#8217;s able to keep up the pace,</span>&#8221; Clément explains.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">Everything we distribute is Made in France, including the packaging for our products. We&#8217;re also proud to offer products that come from partnerships with major brands and famous designers like Saint James, Agnès B, and Princesse Tam-Tam.</span>”</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19845" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5;" alt="etendue-catalogue" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/etendue-catalogue.png" width="494" height="301" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #337f97;">From an Online Store to Brick and Mortar, With the Help of the &#8220;Slip Truck&#8221;</h2>
<p><strong>It took less than three years for Le Slip Français to find a home with <a href="http://www.leslipfrancais.fr/en/content/16-stockists" target="_blank">over sixty retailers</a></strong>, including the emblematic Galeries Lafayette in Paris.</p>
<p>In July 2014, the company set off to conquer the beaches of France with its Slip Truck, a van offering made-in-France briefs and swimsuits to vacationing tourists. The truck was one of the first steps Le Slip Français took towards brick-and-mortar commerce.</p>
<p>In October 2014, while the company was migrating to PrestaShop 1.6 for the third version of its site, it opened its first physical store in Paris.</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19844" alt="estafette-slip-francais" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/estafette-slip-francais.jpg" width="350" height="218" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19842" alt="shop" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/boutique.png" width="306" height="307" /></div>
</div>
<h2 style="color: #337f97;">The Recipe for Success: PrestaShop 1.6, Helping Le Slip Français Succeed</h2>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19856" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5;" alt="homepage" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/homepage.png" width="333" height="589" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12">When I asked Clément for the recipe for success for Le Slip Français, PrestaShop was the first ingredient he mentioned: &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">We&#8217;ve always relied on the PrestaShop platform, from Guillaume&#8217;s first steps and our major media campaigns to where we are today. The platform has been with our business as we&#8217;ve grown in terms of design and features, and is very capable of handling spikes in traffic.</span>&#8220;For its recent migration to PrestaShop 1.6, the Le Slip team worked with <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/platinum/newquest" target="_blank">NewQuest</a>, a PrestaShop-certified agency. This new version <strong>has brought lots of new features and optimizations to the online store</strong>. &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">We&#8217;re very happy to have upgraded to PrestaShop version 1.6. The change in interfaces is incredible,</span>&#8221; Clement says.</div>
</div>
<p>Whenever the brand appears on TV or is mentioned in a national newspaper, there can be a major increase in traffic. After their appearance on the TF1 evening newscast in September 2012, there were <strong>more than 5,000 simultaneous connections to the site, and around 15,000 connections in the 5 minutes following the broadcast of the report</strong>.</p>
<p>Yann Costes, founder of NewQuest, explains: &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;"><strong>PrestaShop naturally manages traffic spikes</strong>. In the case of Le Slip Français, its store and database are hosted on different servers, which allows them to handle a large increase in traffic at any time. We can also add additional servers and a load balancer to guarantee 100% site uptime for special promotions on major media outlets.</span>&#8221;</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19848" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5;" alt="mobile version" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/mobile1-575x1024.png" width="345" height="614" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19849" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5;" alt="mobile version" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/mobile2-575x1024.png" width="345" height="614" /></div>
</div>
<p>Upgrading from PrestaShop 1.3 to 1.6 also helped the brand implement a number of new features. In addition to <strong>a mobile version of the site and emails</strong> (which led to more than a 10% increase in sales in that channel), <strong>abandoned cart reminders</strong>, and automatic promotions for <strong>customer birthdays</strong>, NewQuest made several customizations that are unique to the store.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19843" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5;" alt="map France" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/cms-fabrication-727x1024.png" width="448" height="630" /></p>
<p><strong>CMS page management</strong> was adapted to fit as closely as possible to the brand&#8217;s needs. Pages like &#8220;<a href="http://www.leslipfrancais.fr/en/timeline?fr%2Ftimeline=" target="_blank">The History of Briefs</a>&#8221; and &#8220;<a href="http://www.leslipfrancais.fr/en/content/6-madeinfrance" target="_blank">100% Made in France</a>&#8221; were custom created, then the CMS interfaces of the PrestaShop back office were adapted to the content.</p>
<p>Another feature unique to Le Slip Français is how photos from social networks can be shared directly to the product page in question. By associating a unique hashtag with each product, the team at Le Slip Français can monitor posts and share content from them on product pages. This <strong>helps strengthen the brand&#8217;s sense of community</strong> and presents the products in another light.<br />
For email campaigns, <strong>the store is connected to <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/18921-official-mailchimp-for-prestashop-16.html" target="_blank">MailChimp</a></strong>. Customers who sign up for the newsletter are automatically segmented by profile and purchases. It’s basically the age-old question: &#8220;Boxers or briefs?&#8221;</p>
<p>Le Slip Français uses <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/8334-be2bill-internet-payment-paiement-simple.html" target="_blank">Be2Bill</a> and <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/1748-paypal.html" target="_blank">PayPal</a> for its online payments. Logistics, which had initially been managed in Guillaume&#8217;s garage, are <strong>now completely outsourced</strong> with Logtex using EDI to send and track orders, and connected to Fastmag ERP software for inventory management.</p>
<p>The company doesn&#8217;t run many AdWords or retargeting campaigns. <strong>Thanks to PrestaShop&#8217;s natural SEO, the brand is <a href="https://www.google.fr/?gws_rd=ssl#q=slip" target="_blank">number one in France for the keyword &#8220;briefs&#8221;</a></strong> (remember <a href="https://www.google.fr/?gws_rd=ssl#q=tablier" target="_blank">Madame Choup and her aprons</a>, <a href="https://www.google.fr/?gws_rd=ssl#q=chaise" target="_blank">4-pieds and their chairs</a>, and <a href="https://www.google.fr/?gws_rd=ssl#q=chaussettes" target="_blank">the Archiduchesse&#8217;s socks</a>…?).</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19850" style="border: 1px solid #dce1e5;" alt="Yahoo Japan" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/yahoo-japan.png" width="394" height="325" /></p>
<p>Thanks to its strong values, the brand now has over <strong>50,000 fans and nearly 10,000 followers</strong>. &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">Our community is like our playground,</span>&#8221; Clément explains. &#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">It&#8217;s incredibly supportive. <a href="http://www.mymajorcompany.com/sentez-bon-du-slip" target="_blank">Our crowdfunding campaign for &#8220;briefs that smell good&#8221;</a> brought in more than €22,000 instead of the €10,000 we had hoped for!</span>&#8221; The company is doing an excellent job of capitalizing on the buzz. Its &#8220;Surprise du Chef&#8221; (&#8220;Chef&#8217;s Surprise&#8221;) video has nearly one million views on YouTube, and even made the front page of <a href="http://videotopics.yahoo.co.jp/videolist/official/others/pc3cffe09e04afe3f0ec6878684b4dfd3" target="_blank">Yahoo Japan</a>!</p>
<h2 style="color: #337f97;">The Future of Le Slip: International Expansion</h2>
<p>Le Slip has quite a few plans in the works with PrestaShop. The first is conquering international markets.</p>
<p>&#8220;<span style="font-style: italic;">Le Slip Français has already had some success in Western Europe (Belgium, Germany, and the United Kingdom) and Asia. 2015 will be our year for international growth. Soon our site will be translated into German and Chinese. These versions will use PrestaShop&#8217;s multistore feature, which will give us completely localized front offices with specific domain names,</span>&#8221; Clément says.</p>
<p>They plan to use PrestaShop 1.6&#8242;s shared inventory feature to <strong>centralize inventories</strong> between the physical and online stores.</p>
<p>Finally, there&#8217;s also <strong>a WordPress blog interfaced with PrestaShop</strong> in the works: product pages will link to articles that mention them, and vice-versa.</p>
<p>Much more can be said about the success of Le Slip Français&#8230; <strong>check out the key figures in this infographic!</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19847" alt="Infographic" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/LSFInfographic_EN-01.jpg" width="1280" height="11059" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/le-slip-francais-friendly-bet-international-success/">Le Slip Français: From Friendly Bet to International Success</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/le-slip-francais-friendly-bet-international-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is your ecommerce store ready for Google’s mobile-friendly update?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-store-ready-googles-mobile-friendly-update/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-store-ready-googles-mobile-friendly-update/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 15:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gary Le Masson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Breaking news: starting April 21st, only mobile and responsive sites will appear in Google search results on mobile devices. If you read my predictions for ecommerce in 2015, then Google’s announcement probably isn’t a big surprise&#8211;I was pretty sure this would be the year of mobile. So what does this mean for you as an [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-store-ready-googles-mobile-friendly-update/">Is your ecommerce store ready for Google’s mobile-friendly update?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Breaking news: starting April 21st, only mobile and responsive sites will appear <a href="http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.fr/2015/02/finding-more-mobile-friendly-search.html" target="_blank">in Google search results on mobile devices</a>. If you read my <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-seo-trends-for-2015/">predictions for ecommerce in 2015</a>, then Google’s announcement probably isn’t a big surprise&#8211;I was pretty sure this would be the year of mobile.<br />
<span id="more-19829"></span><br />
So what does this mean for you as an ecommerce store owner? Simply put, if your website theme is not mobile or responsive, you won’t show up in search results on phones of any size or make. The customer browsing for a Mother’s Day gift on his phone? He won’t see your selection of hand-knitted sweaters in Peruvian wool. The frazzled customer who needs to order invitations for a party from her smartphone? She will never see your enticing catalog of custom-designed letterpress stationary.</p>
<p>It might be a bit tough to swallow, but as an ecommerce merchant, you don’t really have a choice anymore; you must be mobile compatible. While the stakes are high, the investment doesn’t have to be. Here’s what you need to do.</p>
<p>If you worked with an agency to set up your site, get in touch with them. Tell them you want to switch to a mobile-compatible theme.<br />
If you’re on your own or don’t have the budget for an agency, you can change your theme yourself, but you’ll need to factor in a little extra time. But trust me, it’s time that will pay off.</p>
<ol>
<li>Browse the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/3-templates-prestashop">PrestaShop mobile-responsive themes</a> on the Addons marketplace.</li>
<li>Buy and install your new theme.</li>
<li>Test your site. Check to see that images are the right size and resolution, and that everything displays nicely on various mobile devices.</li>
<li>Take advantage of Mcommerce!</li>
</ol>
<p>If you still have doubts, do this test (before it’s no longer possible): using your smartphone or tablet, search for any product keyword online. Visit sites that are mobile responsive and others that aren’t. The difference in quality should be enough to prove why sites that aren’t mobile responsive are going the way of the dodo.</p>
<p>For a full selection of mobile-responsive templates, visit the Addons Marketplace. Our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">partner agencies</a> are more than happy to consult with you as well.<br />
Have you upgraded to a mobile-responsive theme? How did it go? Do you have any recommendations for other merchants? Let us know in the comments. Ready to launch your own mobile-responsive ecommerce store? <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">Create your online store now with PrestaShop</a> today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-store-ready-googles-mobile-friendly-update/">Is your ecommerce store ready for Google’s mobile-friendly update?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-store-ready-googles-mobile-friendly-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop Modules: Customizing the look of your homepage</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 13:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like most PrestaShop merchants, the first thing you’re probably itching to do after installing your shop is add your own personal touch by customizing design. From uploading your logo to adding images, we agree&#8211;it’s the most fun part about building an online store! So today we&#8217;re going to show you how to modify [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/">PrestaShop Modules: Customizing the look of your homepage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like most PrestaShop merchants, the first thing you’re probably itching to do after installing your shop is add your own personal touch by customizing design. From uploading your logo to adding images, we agree&#8211;it’s the most fun part about building an online store! So today we&#8217;re going to show you how to modify your homepage.<br />
<span id="more-19796"></span><br />
To help you start customizing your home page, here are some modules we think you’ll like. They’re easy to access through the PrestaShop Back office under the “Modules” tab.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19798" alt="header" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/header.jpg" width="600" height="393" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">Modules above the fold</h2>
<p>&#8220;Above the fold&#8221; is a concept borrowed from the newspapers. Originally, it referred to the practice of placing the most important articles above the newspaper fold. This concept has made its way to the web and now also refers to the content on a webpage that is visible to a visitor without having to scroll. Anything “above the fold” is the first thing your customers see when they land on your page. Here are the modules that give you control over this portion of your shop:</p>
<ol style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Banner Block</li>
<li>Contact Block</li>
<li>Preferences &gt; Themes &gt; Logo Tab &gt; Header Logo</li>
<li>Quick Search Block (only enable and disable)</li>
<li>Top horizontal Menu</li>
<li>Image slider (homepage)</li>
<li>Theme Configurator &gt; Hook “Top”</li>
</ol>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19799" alt="template" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/template.jpg" width="600" height="656" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">Modules in the Body</h2>
<p>Our default template offers many opportunities for conversions once your customer starts scrolling through the home page. We start by featuring your products, then we include large advertising blocks that help highlight product categories. Finally, we close the section with CMS blocks to help you build credibility.</p>
<ol style="padding-left: 30px" start="8">
<li>New products block</li>
<li>Featured products (homepage)</li>
<li>Top-Sellers block</li>
<li>Theme Configurator &gt; Hook “Body”</li>
<li>Facebook Like block</li>
<li>Custom CMS information block</li>
</ol>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19797" alt="footer" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/footer.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #71bd39">Modules in the Footer</h2>
<p>PrestaShop’s default theme gives you a large footer on every page. Whether your customers are on a product, category or even CMS page, they can access the information provided in the footer.<br />
The first section includes a newsletter subscription block to help you collect emails and social media buttons for increasing social awareness. Next, we provide links to important pages on your website, which helps merchants navigate there easily.</p>
<ol style="padding-left: 30px" start="14">
<li>Newsletter block</li>
<li>Social Networking Block</li>
<li>Categories block</li>
<li>CMS block</li>
<li>My account block for your website&#8217;s footer (Enable / Disable)</li>
<li>Contact information block</li>
<li>CMS block</li>
</ol>
<p>What’s your favorite module? Let us know in the comments below. If you’re actively working on your website, bookmark this article to have it easily accessible! Want to learn more about PrestaShop? Check out these resources:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/forums/">PrestaShop Forum</a> (Exchange ideas with our 700,000 member international community)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/newsletter">PrestaShop Newsletter</a> – Get the latest PrestaShop advice delivered straight to your inbox</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/">PrestaShop Modules: Customizing the look of your homepage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Comparing 3 Major Shipping Carriers &#8211; UPS vs. FedEx vs. USPS</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/comparing-3-major-shipping-carriers-ups-vs-fedex-vs-usps/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/comparing-3-major-shipping-carriers-ups-vs-fedex-vs-usps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 13:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19785</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>“Which shipping carrier should I use for my business?” This question usually rears its head as an online seller becomes more successful and consequently, has more orders to ship. To help merchants narrow down and select the right shipping service for their business needs, we’ve asked Olivier Trunkett, from ShippingEasy, to compare the different shipping [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/comparing-3-major-shipping-carriers-ups-vs-fedex-vs-usps/">Comparing 3 Major Shipping Carriers &#8211; UPS vs. FedEx vs. USPS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Which shipping carrier should I use for my business?” This question usually rears its head as an online seller becomes more successful and consequently, has more orders to ship. To help merchants narrow down and select the right shipping service for their business needs, we’ve asked Olivier Trunkett, from ShippingEasy, to compare the different shipping solutions available for merchants in the United States. Read on to see what he shares!<br />
<span id="more-19785"></span><br />
There are three major carriers available in the United States: UPS, FedEx and the United States Postal Service (USPS). These brands are familiar to most Americans and are associated with reliable shipping to consumer residences.</p>
<p>Although each carrier has specific strengths, their differences aren’t as stark as they once were. The carries all have strategies to serve the ecommerce market and continue to improve their pick-up, service, delivery options and tracking to meet online sellers’ (and buyers’) needs. As a result, USPS now has exceptional 1-3 day Priority Mail capabilities, FedEx and UPS offer competitively priced ground solutions, and services like FedEx SmartPost and UPS SurePost leverage USPS for final package delivery to residences buying online.</p>
<p class="text-center" style="font-style: italic"><strong>If carriers are so similar now, how do I pick the best one for my business?</strong></p>
<p>In my experience, online sellers are most concerned with price and reliability. Let’s take a look at how these 3 major carriers stack up on these and other important criteria.</p>
<h2 style="color: #318a1e">United States Postal Service (USPS)</h2>
<p>First, let’s remove the misconception that USPS is not appropriate for a business. Too many sellers still associate USPS with holiday cards, junk mail and bills. In reality, the USPS has improved all of its delivery and ecommerce services and is focused on winning this segment – starting with low prices on the lighter weight items most often ordered online. Let’s see how USPS stacks up.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Price:</strong></span> USPS is the cheapest shipping solution for packages under 2 pounds. If the package is less than 13oz there is literally no comparison. (Most other carrier rates start from 1 lb. or 16 oz.) USPS offers a service called First Class Mail for shipping packages up to 13oz, <a href="http://shippingeasy.com/uspsdiscountedratetable/" target="_blank">starting at .93</a>, if you’re using an online shipping solution. Or if you head to your local Post Office, retail prices start at $2.32. USPS focuses on being the low-cost provider, and in most cases they succeed. Their Priority Mail service has improved its delivery times, provides delivery date estimates based on zone and further reduced their rates in late 2014. They also offer extremely competitive <a href="http://shippingeasy.com/uspsdiscountedratetable/" target="_blank">flat rate boxes and unique regional rate boxes</a> for heavier packages.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Extra Fees:</strong></span> USPS doesn’t tack on the surcharges all too common with UPS and FedEx – namely for residential delivery and fuel surcharges. They also offer free package pickup and Saturday delivery at no extra charge. My advice is to make sure that you look at the “total cost to deliver” with all surcharges when comparing carriers. All too often sellers just look at the base cost.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Reliability:</strong></span> This is USPS’s Achilles heel. Its reputation was tarnished long ago, and despite a vast improvements in the last 3 years, trust takes a long time to rebuild. After working with thousands of sellers since 2012, their improved point-to-point tracking seems to be winning over online sellers. On the other hand, USPS doesn’t always guarantee delivery time, but rather refunds postage in the event that a package doesn’t arrive on time. Many sellers look for more reassurance with items that absolutely must arrive overnight – and are not interested in a claims process. This might mean you’ll want to use a private carrier for time-sensitive packages.</p>
<h2 style="color: #318a1e">Federal Express (FedEx)</h2>
<p>FedEx has an excellent reputation and a brand name that just might impress your customers. You might want to consider this carrier for time-sensitive packages or high-value items where a trusted brand is crucial to your customers.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Price:</strong></span> FedEx can be more expensive than UPS on their expedited services like overnight and 2-day shipping; however, they can be very competitive on rates when it comes to ground shipping, even when compared to USPS.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Discounted Rates:</strong></span> While UPS rates have to be negotiated in person, FedEx has started to initiate discounted rates on some services using online specials. Access is as simple as signing up for an online account. It’s worth doing a Google search with “FedEx online specials” and other keyword variations to see what new offers are available.<br />
Extra Fees: FedEx and UPS will tack on fees for things like residential delivery (costly for online sellers), fuel surcharges, Saturday delivery and package pickup unless you are a large shipper with daily pick up.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Reliability:</strong></span> FedEx takes delivery time very seriously, and all but guarantee a package will arrive when they say it will, except in rare circumstances such as extreme weather and holidays.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Tracking:</strong></span> Tracking individual packages with FedEx works very well. Numerous scans keep track of packages throughout their journey and useful information is available at every checkpoint.</p>
<h2 style="color: #318a1e">United Parcel Service (UPS)</h2>
<p>UPS actually delivers more packages ordered online than any other carrier. You can think of “brown” as the market leader, with USPS and FedEx competing fiercely for your business. In this case, competition is good for you and your bottom line!</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Price:</strong></span> General opinion is that UPS ground shipping is great for packages that weigh in at the 2lb+ mark. While this may be true, negotiated rates play a big role in determining what is ultimately cheaper. You will want to compare your negotiated rates – fully loaded with the applicable surcharges – to rates from the other carriers to determine what’s actually cheaper.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Discounted Rates:</strong></span> It’s up to you to negotiate your UPS rates directly with an Account Manager based on your delivery volume. Use your network as a starting point to both leverage their advice and ballpark rates for various “net minimum” volumes. This will help you evaluate the offered rates. Make sure to get a clear explanation of all surcharges and then add these to establish a “total cost” if you’re planning to compare to other carriers. You want an &#8220;apples to apples&#8221; comparison; too often I see sellers look at the bare bones price instead of the fully loaded price. You can expect a nasty surprise at the end of the month on your invoice if you’re not careful.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Extra Fees:</strong></span> UPS tacks on extra fees just like FedEx, and doesn’t have any free package pickup service that I know of.</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Delivery Reliability:</strong></span> Just like FedEx, UPS takes delivery reliability very seriously, rarely suffering delays (other than that rotten holiday back in 2013).</p>
<p><span style="color: #02587b"><strong>Tracking:</strong></span> UPS has some of the best tracking for online sellers, with innovative features such as package update text messages available to customers.</p>
<h2 style="color: #318a1e">Deciding on a Shipping Carrier</h2>
<p>To pick the best carrier for your shipments, you want to have a good idea of your shipping profile. Ask yourself the following questions:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30xp">
<li>What does my average order weigh?</li>
<li>What is the maximum and minimum weight of my orders?</li>
<li>What sort of boxes or envelopes or poly mailers am I likely to use?</li>
</ul>
<p>Weight, dimensions and distance are what drive shipping cost for both you and the carrier. Once you have an idea of what you’ll be shipping and packaging, you’re ready to compare the rates, services and delivery options from each carrier. For example, if you ship lightweight apparel, you will find USPS First Class shipping hard to beat. When packages start to hit the 2 lb. mark, you will want to explore the ground services offered by all three carriers, and compare the fully loaded cost and average delivery times of each. Inexpensive items that don’t have to be shipped within a precise timeframe might be suited for FedEx and UPS’ low-cost shipping solutions SmartPost and SurePost.</p>
<p>Many sellers mix and match shipping services depending on common order types. If you’re shipping less than 50 orders per month, you might want to start with USPS where the <a href="http://shippingeasy.com/usps-rates-by-plan/" target="_blank">rates are readily available</a> and you don’t need an account, invoicing or negotiations. As you grow, you’ll have the volume to make your negotiations more successful and your options plentiful with the private carriers!</p>
<p>We’ve highlighted the main benefits of each shipping carrier in the chart below:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19807" alt="tab" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/majoruscamparison.jpg" width="759" height="538" /></p>
<hr align="center" width="20%" />
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19787" alt="shippingeasy" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/shippingeasy.png" width="220" height="127" /></p>
<p>Ready to start shipping products from your online store? Get started by installing ShippingEasy’s module directly from your back office, or downloading the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules/19038-prestashippingeasy.html" target="_blank">ShippingEasy Module</a> from PrestaShop Addons.</p>
<p>Through their service, you’ll get:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>46% Savings off USPS Rates</li>
<li>Easy carrier integration with USPS, UPS and FedEx</li>
<li>FREE starter plan for up to 50 shipments per month</li>
<li>Exceptional customer support</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/comparing-3-major-shipping-carriers-ups-vs-fedex-vs-usps/">Comparing 3 Major Shipping Carriers &#8211; UPS vs. FedEx vs. USPS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/comparing-3-major-shipping-carriers-ups-vs-fedex-vs-usps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are PrestaShop Modules?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19769</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As a PrestaShop user, you should be pretty familiar with the term “module.” You might even have heard of front office modules, back office modules and official modules. But what exactly is a module anyway? Today Chris Machin explains the concept of modules, what they are, and how to use them to maximize your PrestaShop [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules/">What are PrestaShop Modules?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a PrestaShop user, you should be pretty familiar with the term “module.” You might even have heard of <span style="font-style: italic">front office modules</span>, <span style="font-style: italic">back office modules</span> and <span style="font-style: italic">official modules</span>. But what exactly is a module anyway?</p>
<p>Today Chris Machin explains the concept of modules, what they are, and how to use them to maximize your PrestaShop store. As a Partner Manager, he works side by side with other companies to create <span style="font-style: italic">connector modules</span> – but more on that later!<br />
<span id="more-19769"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #509924">Why does PrestaShop use Modules?</h2>
<p>The PrestaShop software is used by over 200,000 online shops around the world. They run the retail gamut from selling digital products (<a href="http://dulzuradepapel.com/" target="_blank">Dulzura de Papel</a>) to clothing (<a href="http://myindiesoul.com/" target="_blank">Indie Soul</a>). Although these companies sell online, they use the PrestaShop software in different ways. PrestaShop was built with the need for versatility in mind. To accommodate a variety of business needs without weighing down the software, these features can be turned on or off by installing or removing modules.</p>
<p>So what does this look like in actual practice? Well, our own PrestaShop Addons is a marketplace-based shop, where independent users submit their products to be sold (a little like Amazon Marketplace). Indie Soul, on the other hand, is a traditional fashion retailer, so they don’t need the marketplace functionality. However, they ship their products so they need features that help them do that efficiently.</p>
<h2 style="color: #509924">What is a module?</h2>
<p>At PrestaShop, we define a module as an extension that adds functionality to the PrestaShop software. Modules can also be referred to as integrations, plug-ins or widgets. They add functionality in the following ways:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Customize displayed content</li>
<li>Perform tasks</li>
<li>Connect with other tools (API)</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="color: #94c3df">Modules that customize displays</h4>
<p>With these modules, you can modify everything from your homepage banner to the content displayed in your menu bar. The most popular module that allows modifications to PrestaShop’s default template is our &#8220;Theme configurator&#8221; module, which is built directly into the back office and lets you enable or disable many front office displays including the Facebook Block, CMS information, Top Banner and others.</p>
<h4 style="color: #94c3df">Modules that perform various tasks</h4>
<p>There are as many modules as there are business challenges. For example, do you want to reward customers for making purchases, but find it difficult to keep track of who bought what? With PrestaShop’s built in loyalty and rewards module, you can automatically reward frequent customers for shopping on your website with a loyalty program.</p>
<p>That’s just one example of the added functionality a task-performing module can provide. Others can batch update information, such as search queries and exchange rates, or help you batch import and export data from your shop.</p>
<h4 style="color: #94c3df">Modules that connect with other tools</h4>
<p>Once you’re up and running, you’ll quickly find that you use many different software programs and service providers along with PrestaShop to run your online store. For example, regardless of what type of payment you accept, you’ll need a payment processor to handle the actual cash exchange.</p>
<p>To help your PrestaShop store communicate with your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/set-up-payment-module">payment provider</a>, we partner with them to provide a free module which connects to their API (Application Program Interface). This API contains a set of routines, protocols and tools that communicates data such as payment status, exchange rates, and shipping costs to your PrestaShop store, which is then displayed back to the customer.</p>
<p>In our payment provider example, PrestaShop’s software will send the customer’s billing information along with the order amount to your preferred payment provider. Once the payment processor has completed the transaction, the confirmation information is sent back to your PrestaShop software and stored in the order information database.</p>
<p>Payment processing is just one of the many free modules PrestaShop provides. We work with a number of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners">partners in the following industries</a>:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Shipping</li>
<li>Marketing</li>
<li>Operations</li>
<li>Marketplaces</li>
<li>Emailing</li>
<li>Payment</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #509924">Getting Started</h2>
<p>To explore the many functions and features that come pre-built into PrestaShop, head to the Modules tab in your PrestaShop Back Office. Once you’ve had a look around the many features we offer, explore <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Addons</a>, our official marketplace, to access the thousands of modules developed by members in our community.</p>
<p>Already familiar with our modules? Tell us which is your favorite in the comments below!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules/">What are PrestaShop Modules?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce 101: What is an ecommerce software?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-ecommerce-software/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-ecommerce-software/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19745</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you a seasoned developer finding it hard to explain what a shopping cart solution is to your clients? Or a future online merchant researching ecommerce software options for your store? Regardless of why you’re asking yourself “What is an ecommerce software?”, today’s blog post should give you a clear answer to your question. Ecommerce [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-ecommerce-software/">Ecommerce 101: What is an ecommerce software?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you a seasoned developer finding it hard to explain what a shopping cart solution is to your clients? Or a future online merchant researching <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/">ecommerce software</a> options for your store?</p>
<p>Regardless of why you’re asking yourself “What is an ecommerce software?”, today’s blog post should give you a clear answer to your question.<br />
<span id="more-19745"></span></p>
<p>Ecommerce software&#8211;also called a shopping cart solution, shopping cart software, ecommerce website builder, online store builder or ecommerce platform&#8211;has one purpose:</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><span style="color: #000000"><strong>To help you sell products online.</strong></span></p>
<p>A shopping cart solution’s core functions are to manage three areas critical to running a successful online shop:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Products</li>
<li>Orders</li>
<li>Customers</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s explore how ecommerce software helps you manage each of these areas.</p>
<h2 style="color: #74bc3f"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="tag" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/tag.png" width="50" height="50" /> Product Catalog</h2>
<p>Before you can sell online, you need to determine what you’re going to sell – in other words, your products. They can be physical products, such as shirts or computers, or they can be <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/">digital products</a>, like music or <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/3-templates-prestashop">themes</a>.</p>
<p>Whatever you decide to sell, you’ll need a product catalog to manage it all. Your catalog helps you store the following information about your products:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Name</li>
<li>Description</li>
<li>Price</li>
<li>Image(s)</li>
<li>Quantity in Stock</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition to the basic information, your product catalog can also include advanced features like:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Product Attributes like size and color – offer customers further options</li>
<li>Associated Products – bundle complementary products to prompt sales</li>
<li>Reference Numbers – organize your products</li>
<li>Product Categories – group products into categories to improve shopper experience</li>
<li>Product Customization – customize the product with personal images or text</li>
<li>SEO (Friendly URL’s, Meta Tags) – help potential customers find your product</li>
<li>Coupons and Discounts – give customers incentives to make the purchase</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #74bc3f"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="panier" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/panier.png" width="50" height="50" /> Ordering System</h2>
<p>Now that you can display your products, your customers can shop for them. This is where the ordering system comes into play. It allows customers to add items to their cart, calculates the total price and captures information necessary to process the order.</p>
<p>Some of the information captured during the order process includes:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Product(s) Purchased</li>
<li>Fees associated with the order (shipping)</li>
<li>Shipping Addresses</li>
<li>Billing Address</li>
<li>Payment Method</li>
</ul>
<p>Additional Features:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Integration with <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/set-up-payment-module">payment processors</a> – allows you to accept payment to complete purchases on the spot.</li>
<li>Integration with a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/6-shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules">shipping solution</a> – syncs order information with a shipping solution to seamlessly process orders</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">Order System &amp; Product Catalog</span><br />
The order system’s job is not complete once an order is placed. The order system then deducts the number of products sold from your inventory so that your product catalog reflects the correct number of products available for sale.</p>
<h2 style="color: #74bc3f"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="user" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/03/user.png" width="50" height="50" /> Customer Management</h2>
<p>The last piece of a shopping cart solution is customer management. The merchant-customer relationship shouldn’t end when an order is complete. While you hope that customers come back for a repeat purchase, sometimes that relationship requires handling their requests for exchanges or returns. These don’t have to be entirely negative experiences; you can turn them into opportunities for demonstrating your excellent customer service.</p>
<p>So, a shopping cart software should also help manage customers by collecting and storing the following information:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Customer Name</li>
<li>Contact Info (Email or Phone)</li>
<li>Shipping Address</li>
<li>Order History</li>
</ul>
<p>Other helpful information to have include:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Billing Address – to expedite the reorder and refund process</li>
<li>Birthday – for birthday marketing and age verification</li>
<li>Order History by Product – to better understand which products they love</li>
<li>Registration Date – to know how long they’ve been customers</li>
<li>Contact History – to be aware of previous customer interaction</li>
</ul>
<p>The rise in the number of online merchants has prompted an increase in the number of shopping cart solutions on the market competing for their attention. But PrestaShop is proud to be the only one with a community of over 700,000 people across the world contributing to its continued development. An open source software, our <a href="https://github.com/PrestaShop/PrestaShop">community on GitHub</a> has helped add over 300 features to our solution. For an updated list of our newest features check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-v-1-6-back-office-whats-new-and-improved/">latest major software release</a>.</p>
<p>Visit our website to explore <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/shopping-cart">more of our features</a> or jump right in and <a href="http://demo.prestashop.com/en/?view=back">take our demo</a> for a test drive. Have more questions about the basics of a shopping cart software? Fire away in the comments below!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-ecommerce-software/">Ecommerce 101: What is an ecommerce software?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-ecommerce-software/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>11 SEO questions you need to answer before starting an online store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/11-seo-questions-need-answer-starting-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/11-seo-questions-need-answer-starting-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 08:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gary Le Masson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19742</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Search engine optimization: you know it’s important and you know you have to do it. But where do you start? After all, there are people who spend all day, every day doing nothing but SEO. You, on the other hand, are a busy online business owner with more priorities than you can count. Fear not. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/11-seo-questions-need-answer-starting-online-store/">11 SEO questions you need to answer before starting an online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search engine optimization: you know it’s important and you know you have to do it. But where do you start? After all, there are people who spend all day, every day doing nothing but SEO. You, on the other hand, are a busy online business owner with more priorities than you can count.</p>
<p>Fear not. Underneath all the acronyms, keywords and links, SEO is just marketing applied to the web. It’s a relatively simple, easy to apply strategy that admittedly demands patience, but that with a little planning, any ecommerce entrepreneur can wield to their advantage.</p>
<p>As PrestaShop’s resident SEO guru, I’ve put together the 11 SEO questions you need to ask—and answer—before launching your online store. The questions build on one another to construct a simple SEO strategy that covers all the basics. If you follow my advice, you’ve got a good chance of breaking through the noise and rocketing to the top of search results.</p>
<p>Here we go&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-19742"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">1. Who am I selling to?</h2>
<p>Before you start brainstorming keywords or developing a social media strategy, or even writing product descriptions, you need to know exactly who your audience is. This is basic marketing criteria than any business, online or offline, must establish. Consider these two questions:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What problem or desire does my product respond to?</li>
<li>What is my ideal customer looking for?</li>
</ul>
<p>Sit down and think about your ideal customers. Who are they? What motivates them to search for the products you’re selling? Creating <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">customer personas</a> is a vital first step that will help you home in on your target audience and focus your marketing efforts accordingly.</p>
<p>You can do all the SEO you like, but until your audience is crystal clear, none of it will be of any service to your online business.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">2. What search engine key words should my ecommerce store rank on?</h2>
<p>Now that you know who you’re talking to, make sure you’re using their vocabulary. Make a list of all the words that relate to your product and sector, and also more specific “long tail” combinations that your customers might use to search for your products.</p>
<p>The more specific your keywords are, the more likely you are to respond to a particular customer need. (i.e. “non-stick heart-shaped cake pan” versus simply “cake pan”). These <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">keywords</a> will help you determine your site structure, write compelling product pages and generate meaningful content.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">3. What keywords do my competitors rank on?</h2>
<p>When it comes to SEO, there are two types of competition:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Search competition</li>
<li>Real competition</li>
</ul>
<p>Search competition is everything that appears when you enter your keywords, from Wikipedia pages to news articles; these results share the same search universe as your store and compete for user attention.</p>
<p>Real competition comes from competitors in your sector selling similar products. They’re competing for user attention and user dollars.</p>
<p>Don’t copy your real competitors, but keep tabs on what they are doing and try to identify how you can differentiate yourself and position your ecommerce store on specific keywords that reflect your expertise, specialty or unique differentiator.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">4. Is my catalogue strong enough to rank my store on my key words?</h2>
<p>You’ve identified your keywords, you know what your competitors are doing. Now it’s time to look at your catalog and make sure it’s up to the task of ranking your site. Just because you create a page for dresses doesn’t mean you’ll show up in any searches.</p>
<p>I once met a business owner who couldn’t figure out why his store didn’t appear in search results for “men’s face cream.” So I asked him, “How many creams do you carry?” His response: “Three.” Clearly, he was not going to stand out from all the other stores with dozens of references for “men’s face cream.”</p>
<p>The internet is a bewildering sea of information. You are guaranteed to drown in it if you don’t have a strategy. You either need to have a strong catalog with many references corresponding to your keywords or own an incredibly specific and highly specialized niche.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">5. Does my store website structure correspond to my key words?</h2>
<p>You know who you’re selling to, you’ve got your keywords figured out and you have a strong catalog. Now that you’re done with the theory, you can get down to mapping out your online store.</p>
<p>Remember that you’re creating a store to please customers, not search engines. Building a site that ranks requires a combination of attention to keywords and user experience. Read my article on using keywords to <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-use-your-seo-keywords-to-structure-your-ecommerce-site/">structure</a> your ecommerce site for an in-depth tutorial.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">6. Do my product pages respond to actual customer questions?</h2>
<p>You’ve developed a beautiful site architecture; now it’s time to populate it with super informative product pages. Remember, you’re not writing them to rank on Google; you’re writing them to provide a service to your customers.</p>
<p>If your online store is akin to a brick and mortar shop, then your product pages stand in for your expert sales staff. Answer all your customers’ questions—including the ones they didn’t even know they had—and you generate trust, build loyalty and increase conversions. And that’s how you rank on Google.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">7. How do I get people talking about my store?</h2>
<p>You can have the greatest product ever made, but if no one knows about it, your business isn’t going to get far. Take some time to think about your sector: who are the influencers? Who do people turn to for advice and recommendations? Those are the people you want to know about your online store.</p>
<p>If you’re a women’s apparel retailer, start cultivating relationships with high-profile fashion bloggers. Or maybe you sell perfume: send samples to a few bloggers and ask them to review your products on their site. The backlinks from these respected sites will put in front of your target audience and increase your own reputation.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">8. Should I have my own blog?</h2>
<p>When we talk about blogs, we’re really talking about <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/content-marketing-for-ecommerce-technical-checklist-writing-process/">content marketing</a>. A blog gives you the opportunity to highlight your expertise, as well as your products. A blog is where you can give advice and explanations that create meaningful content. And Google loves meaningful content.</p>
<p>The big question is how to make your blog work for you. A blog is most valuable when it generates customer loyalty. You might think about (judiciously) using pop-ups to encourage people to subscribe to your newsletter or using incentives for “liking” on Facebook or tweeting helpful articles. You’ll create a valuable database with your newsletter and increase your visibility through social shares.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">9. What is my social media strategy?</h2>
<p>If you have a blog, you’re half way to having a social media strategy. But before you go wild on Vine, remember that social media is likely to give you visibility, but it doesn’t guarantee ranking high on search results. Social media is a secondary activity that should come once you’ve answered the previous SEO questions.</p>
<p>If you’re just starting out, the minimum requirements for establishing your social media presence are Facebook and Twitter. Then you can add Google+. Pinterest and Instagram are extremely effective if you have highly visual content to share.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">10. How do I tell if my SEO efforts are paying off?</h2>
<p>Testing your SEO strategy is as important as putting it into place—how else will you know if what you’re doing is a waste of time or driving conversions? Use Google Analytics to identify your main sources of traffic and which ones are driving sales. Google Webmaster can give you a glimpse into what keywords are driving traffic. Read my article on the many tools available to measure the impact of your SEO action.</p>
<h2 style="color: #32b5a3">11. Is there more to online marketing than SEO?</h2>
<p>Yes! SEO is a powerful, free way to attract visitors and convert them into customers, but it takes a long time to implement an effective SEO strategy, and the results are not guaranteed. So don’t put all your eggs in one basket; get your SEO in place and then consider including these elements into your online marketing strategy:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><span style="font-style: italic">Google Adwords</span>: SEO gives you free visibility, Google Adwords lets you pay for it. This can also be a great tool to test keywords and see what works before applying them to your SEO strategy.</li>
<li><span style="font-style: italic">Marketplaces</span>: EBay, Amazon, PriceMinster and other online marketplaces can be a great way for a new store to get visibility and ease into the ecommerce business.</li>
<li><span style="font-style: italic">Good, old-fashioned publicity</span>: word-of-mouth recommendations are still the most valuable form of advertising. It should be clear to you and your customers why you are the best place to shop for what they want.</li>
</ul>
<p>Have you optimized your website? What’s working for you? What do you wish you could do better? Let us know!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/11-seo-questions-need-answer-starting-online-store/">11 SEO questions you need to answer before starting an online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/11-seo-questions-need-answer-starting-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
